GLOria Higley



816.665.6639

PROFILE

Experienced information systems professional actively and enthusiastically pursuing a career change to software development.

Currently completing LaunchCode's 20-week immersive coding curriculum learning programming fundamentals with Python and web fundamentals with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

Combining business acumen, content strategy, and software development skills to provide a comprehensive approach to solving business problems and creating exceptional user experiences.

EDUCATION

LC 101

LaunchCode 2017 - Present

Masters of Business Administration

University of Central Missouri 2010 - 2012

Bachelors of Business Administration

University of Central Missouri 2004-2008

CONNECT



github.com/gloriahigley



linkedin.com/in/gloriahigley



about.me/gloriahigley



@zeebolove

LAUNCHCODE PROJECT HIGHLIGHTS

Web Caesar Project

Language: Python Tools: Flask, Git

- Coded a simple web application that prompts a user to submit a string and an integer.
- Once submitted, the program rotates each string character by the provided integer and outputs an encrypted string.

User Signup Project

Language(s): Python, HTML

Tools: Flask, Jinja2 Template Engine, Git

- Coded a user signup form that requires client-side validation for username, email, and password.
- Incorporated error messages and Jinja2 templates that render based on the condition of validation submissions.

Blogz Project

Language(s): Python, HTML, SQL

Tools: Flask, Git, Jinja2 Template Engine, MySQL, Bootstrap

- Coded a fully functional multi-user blog application with a front-end interface and database storage capabilities.
- Includes the ability for multiple users to log in, log out, submit a new blog, view all blog posts held in the database, and view only blog posts written by a specific user.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Knowledge Manager, DST Systems

2016 - Present

 Manage Atlassian Confluence intranet web content and Neocase Knowledge Management system for international company with over 10,000 employees.

Project & Document Manager, *Agspring* 2015 - 2016

- Project managed the collection, review, and analysis of due diligence documents for mergers and acquisitions.
- Collaborated with all departments to configure SharePoint sites, define information architecture, and define document management strategy.

Regional Enrollment Manager, Assurant Employee Benefits 2010 - 2015

- Held various positions of increasing scope beginning with a sales support role leading to promotions in project leadership and ultimately management functions.
- As a Regional Enrollment Manager I managed a national cloud-based telephonic enrollment center including reporting, training, troubleshooting, and expansion strategy.